CURRICULUM VITAE

ANAND J SUTHAR

21, Shivdarshan Bungalows, Opp. Poonam Bungalows

Kadi - 382715.

Mobile no.: 09998884932

Email ID: anandsuthar92@gmail.com

Career Summary:

An instrumentation & Control engineer with over 7 years' experience in pharmaceuticals, I have experience in large organizations with equipment qualification, validation, analytical instrument maintenance & Project Planning. My strengths lie in strategy building process and systems, improving efficiency with Clear Communication, decision-maker & Problem solver.

OBJECTIVE:

To get experience in the field of Instrumentation & control. Put my best effort and dedicated to the working of the organization with Integrity, commitment, passion and speed.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATION:				
Qualification	Institute	University / Board	Year of Passing	Percentage
B.E (Instrumentation & Control)	Govt.Engg. College, S-28, Gandhinagar	Gujarat Technical University	2009-2013	CPI-6.29 CGPA-7.03
HSC	Shree Sarvavidhyalaya, Kadi	G.H.S.E.B	March 2009	69.80
SSC	Shree Kalyanvidhyalaya, Highschool, Kalyanpura	G.S.E.B	March 2007	84.77

TECHNICAL SKILL:

- > Project Planning & Leadership.
- > Analytical Instruments maintenance.
- ➤ AutoCAD, Equipment Commissioning & Validation.
- > Instrument Calibration & Instrumentation documentation.
- > PLC, SCADA, HMI, DRIVE programming.

PROJECT & TRAINING:

- ➤ I got training
- ➤ I got training at SINE-B AUTOMATION Vatva, Jasodanagar.
- ➤ In which learn about PLC (MITSUBISHI, DELTA, ALLEN BRADLEY AND SIEMENS)
 - SCADA (WONDERWARE INTOUCH.)
 - HMI (MITSUBISHI)

- ➤ I got training at Automation Engineer, paldi, ahmedabad. Learn about micro-controller and C programming. Also, I make final year Project on the "The river bridge automation using microcontroller".
- A Project report and work on "The water level indicator" & "LCD based Digital clock using AT89C51" in B.E. 6th Sem. (2011-2012).

WORK EXPERIENCE:

- ➤ Currently I am working in BAXTER PHARMACEUTICALS INDIA PRIVET LIMITED, Ahmedabad as an Associate Engineer of Technical Projects department from 23.10.2017 to till date.
- ➤ I have 1.6 years experience in **TORRENT PHARMACEUTICALS LIMITED**, **Indrad** as an **EXECUTIVE** (Commissioning Engineer) of **QUALITY ASSURANCE** department from **25.04.2016** to **05.10.17**.
- ➤ I have 1.8 years experience in **CLARIS INJECTABLES LTD**, **Ahmedabad** as an **OFFICER** (Commissioning Engineer) of **QUALITY ASSURANCE** department from **18.08.2014** to **11.04.2016**.
- ➤ I have 7 months experience in UNIVERSAL TECHNOMATION PVT. LTD. as a PROJECT ENGINEER from 11.11.2013 to 30.06.2014.

JOB PROFILE:

In BAXTER PHARMACEUTICALS INDIA PRIVET LIMITED, Ahmedabad.

- ➤ Project Budget forecast Planning, CWIP closing.
- > URS review and vendor visit at site for technical discussion & Offer review.
- > Preparation and approval of RFP (Request for Proposal), Score card and Single Source Justification.
- ➤ Prepare CER (Capital Expenditure Request) and upload in BaxCap Portal for approval.
- > Preparation of BOQ & Data Sheets for Instruments & Automation components as per architecture.
- Review of control logics of utility and process equipment's as per requirements based on P&ID.
- Prepared Project work HIRA (Hazard Identification Risk Assessment).
- > Site Inspection and verification of erection work.
- > Equipment Loading, Unloading, Position desired place and Bill Processing.
- ➤ Details planning, Inspection and execution (FAT, SAT, IQ and OQ) of project.
- Qualification documents Review and proceed for approval, like DQ, FAT, SAT, IQ and OQ.
- Lead the Project and completed within timeline with Capex budget utilization.
- ➤ I have worked on below mention Project and execution and coordination like, DPB, RLAF, VLAF, Autoclave, Bag line Printing matter Inspection machine, HOLOGRAM machine, Leaflet folding machine, WFI Generation, Pure Steam generation, DRO generation and distribution loop, 5TPH and 8TPH Boiler feed water tank installation, Boiler Chimney Installation and modification, Ampoule vial combo labeling machine, Diesel Generator set, LT Panel modification work, stabilizer, AHU installation, Manufacturing Line Volume Size Increase with Automation, Hoist − goods transfer, PCR, Borewell Erection work, Air receiver Tank & Nitrogen tank, Clean room Door installation − facility ceiling, Incubator & isolator, Bios well, trances and recharge borewell cleaning, ETP collection Pit, MBR leakage prevention, Strapping machine, WFI Skid & loop, PSG loop, Hydronic System installation, Micro area instruments installation, Maximo software, Hot Air Oven, Sterilizer SCADA upgradation.

In TORRENT PHARMACEUTICALS LIMITED, Indrad.

- ▶ Planning and execution of Instruments Preventive Maintenance Schedule & Calibration schedule.
- Instruments Breakdown Check and repair like., HPLC (Waters, Shimadzu, Dionex, Agilent), Karl fisher apparatus, Dissolution tester, Disintegration, Micro-balance, Analytical Balance, PH meter, Milli-q, Sonicator bath, Oven, Cooling cabinet, incubator, UV. Maintain related consumable parts.
- > Instruments related given services party coordination and PR, PO activity.
- ➤ Commissioning of Equipments & QC Instruments.
- > Third party calibration of Instruments.

In CLARIS INJECTABLES LTD. Ahmedabad.

- > Planning and execution of Equipments master, monthly Calibration and Qualification schedule.
- ➤ Calibration of Digital Weigh balance, Thermo hygrometer, Magnehelic gauge, Temperature sensor, Pressure Gauge, Conductivity meter, pH meter, Load cell, Oxygen Analyzer, Transmitter.
- ➤ Commissioning of production and Utility Equipments and make related IQ, OQ, PQ documents Likes,
 - ➤ PLC, SCADA, HMI, Double pass Reverse osmosis water purification plant (Auster), Ampoule leak test machine (HM Pharma), Oil free Air compressor with dryer (Ingersoll rand), Automatic Vacuum Pouch Machine (HM Pharma), Automatic blister packing (Formorec) & Autocartonator Machine (Romaco), Ultrasonic vial washing machine (truking), Media Discard Autoclave, PFE 2 Line Atomization, Automatic Bag filling and sealing machine (BFM Plumat)
- ➤ Requalification Study likes, Pure Steam, Silica gel, Bag printing machine, RM-PM Area Temperature mapping, Pinhole machine, VIT booth, KNAPP Batch, Stability chamber, Incubator Temperature mapping, Sterilizer, Autoclave.
- > KAYE Validator, VAL Probe logger programming and software for using validation purpose.

In UNIVERSAL TECHNOMATION PVT. LTD Mahesana

- ➤ I develop PLC, SCADA, HMI, AC Drive & motor-based automation project.
- Designing of electrical wiring and control panel wiring.

AREA OF SPECIAL INTEREST:

- Process Instrumentation.
- > Equipment Commissioning.

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Name : Anand suthar Father Name : Jayantibhai Suthar Date of Birth : 15th Jan 1992

Gender : Male
Nationality : Indian
Mobile no. : 09998884932
Marital Status : Married

Languages Known : English, Hindi, and Gujarati

Hobbies : Reading

DECLARATION:

I hereby declare that information provided above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

riace.	
Date:	(ANAND SUTHAR)